

# Alexander **Schechter**, *PhD*

coderfoundry.com/alexanderschechter

# FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#

**ASP.NET** 

MVC

SQL

LINQ

**JavaScript** 

HTML5

AngularJS

**JQuery** 

**CSS** 

Bootstrap

WebAPI

# CODER FOUNDRY

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284

(336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **University College London**

PhD in Mathematics

London, UK · September 1998-February 2002

#### Universität Kaiserslautern

"Diplom" degree in Mathematics with "sehr gut" grade Germany · September 1993–July 1998

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Coder Foundry, C#/ASP.NET Software Engineer

Kernersville, NC · January 2016-March 2016

- Created a fully functional financial portal web application using .NET MVC framework. Composed dynamic front-end design using partial views and AJAX. Created custom action filters for authorization. Accessed database through LINQ to Entity framework.
- Created a fully functional MVC bug tracker web application from scratch.
   Handled secure file upload functionality for approved file types. Implemented code first database design with user- and role-level security. Database interaction done through LINQ to Entity framework.
- Created a personal portfolio website using C# MVC5 and JavaScript.
  Designed and developed front-end using HTML5, Twitter Bootstrap, and MVC model binding with Razor. Included secure log-in and blog web interface with user comments. Presented programming exercises and code snippets using JavaScript.
- Created a fully functioning car finder web application web application using SQL Stored Procedures. Composed dynamic, responsive front-end design using AngularJS, HTML5 and Twitter Bootstrap. Accessed NHTSA's car recalls database using provided WebAPI to show car recalls. Included images using Bing's WebAPI.

#### **Professional Poker Player**

December 2011-January 2016

- Started as complete beginner and within a year developed to one of the best cash games players in the world, playing the highest stakes available.
- Constant success over 4 years generating in excess of \$1M in profit.
- Produced poker videos for cardrunners.com and coached several players.

## **Lehman Brothers Holding, Derivatives Counterparty Interactor (Director)** *May 2009–December 2011*

- In charge of the external negotiations with the derivatives debtors and creditors.
- In charge of the the internal process of verifying payables and receivables and the coordination between various teams (Trading, Legal and Middle Office).
- Responsible for representing the negotiated proposals to the creditor's committee.

## **Solutions for Wealth, Head of Switzerland and Luxembourg Sales** *August 2008–February 2009*

- Sale of derivatives and funds linked to the FTSE Private Banking Index in a start-up company.
- Account responsibility for all private banking and asset managers in Switzerland and Luxembourg.

# **Dresdner Kleinwort, Private and Retail Banks (Director from April 2007)** *January 2005–July 2008*

- Responsible for building the structured products franchise for Swiss and Luxembourg private and retail banks.
- Focused on equity and interest rate derivatives, as well as marketing other derivatives and structured products.
- Trained and supervised junior salespeople from Oct 2005.

#### **Dresdner Kleinwort, Corporate Solutions Group**

September 2001-January 2005

- Started in the Emerging Europe, Middle East and Africa regions team.
- Moved to the UK and Nordic regions team in mid-2002, where I assumed client responsibility for the first time.
- Focused on interest rate and foreign exchange derivatives hedging.

## **SPECIAL ACHIEVEMENTS**

Apr 2007	Completed the London Marathon and raised ca £3000
	for the Prostate Cancer Charity
Sep 1999 – Sep 2000	President of the UCL Chess Society
0 1 1000 0 1 0001	

Oct 1998 – Sept 2001 Scholarship from the Engineering and Physical Science Research Council

**Dec 1998 – Nov 2001** Scholarship from the Deutscher Akademischer

Auslandsdienst

Oct 1999 Winner of the Davenport Prize in Pure Mathematics for

outstanding research

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Fluent in English, German and Romanian
- Basic in French